# **Dan Cheeseman**

# Front End Developer - Fintech |SaaS

Looking for Remote or Hybrid roles based in Manchester or London.

Manchester City Centre, UK +44 7487 388 823

daniel.cheeseman6@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/dan-che eseman-b1968052/

## PERSONAL STATEMENT

Highly motivated professional with 5+ years of experience in tech, transitioning to a front-end developer role. Since January 2024, I've been intensively learning HTML, CSS, and JavaScript to hone my skills. My experience with APIs and understanding of product development will allow me to contribute effectively to building user interfaces. I'm eager to learn and grow within a collaborative team environment.

#### **PROJECTS**

#### Lead several Frontend initiatives - Total Processing

Built a Knowledge Base template using resources from Zenplates to create a uniform approach to capturing bank knowledge. This includes using inline CSS for styling and JS-Toggles for functionality.

Helped provide support to clients who wished to make styling changes to payment form, this could either be via Shopify Theme Editor via the sCSS files or within a bespoke implementation.

Create user stories for any requested features or functionality for the customer dashboard portal.

#### Built a responsive portfolio site at <a href="https://danichese.github.io/">https://danichese.github.io/</a>

This is currently a work in progress site to help demonstrate my understanding as well as create a landing page of any FrontEnd projects. This really helped me understand responsiveness for different devices and CSS Flexbox. I also used this as an opportunity to learn about Git and Github and how to push changes as well create a landing page with a custom URL.

## **EXPERIENCE**

# **Senior Merchant Support/Technical Onboarding**- Permanent Total Processing, Manchester - Hybrid Aug 2022 - Dec 2023

Created a Trend Analysis Dashboard for Declined transactions with Gen AI, this led to massive improvements in auth rates (75-94% in one case).

Assisted with QA duties such as testing releases to SaaS Dashboard Mastered two distinct payment gateway technologies(ACI and Cybersource), enhancing client payment systems through tailored implementations across different tech stacks such Shopify, Wordpress and API integration.

# Head of Token Operations - Freelance

Goku Token and Luffy Token - Hybrid Oct 2021 - Aug 2022

Joined a small cap crypto project after being asked by the Lead developer. Helped with strategy, investor relations and product testing.

Helped prepare for a multi project migration in terms of testing the Web 3 Swap site as well creating documentation for investors to migrate.

Was responsible for leading investor calls and representing the brand digitally and in person at Crypto Expo Asia 2022 in Singapore.

#### SKILLS/KNOWLEDGE

ITIL

Data Analysis
Team Leadership
Customer Success
SDLC - Agile & Waterfall
Version Control - Git
Project Management

Tech Skills:

HTML

CSS

Javascript

Github

SaaS

Shopify

Wordpress

Stripe API

Copy & Pay API

Lighthouse

Chrome Dev Tools

Semantic HTML

Responsive Design

# Senior Systems Engineer - Contract

Bank of America, Chester - Remote

Dec 2020 - Apr 2022

Joined a mid-flight knowledge service delivery project, transitioning knowledge content, which led to reduced resolution time in the EMEA region.

Provided VIP support at Merrill Lynch, demonstrating versatility in IT service including out of hours support and service delivery requirements.

Led a team of 10 Desktop Support Engineers, overseeing daily operations, guiding technical processes, and driving team performance.

#### Systems Engineer - Contract - Short term.

Parliamentary and Health Service Ombudsman, Manchester - Hybrid Sep 2020 - Dec 2020

Managed system administration using Azure, improving operational efficiency. Oversaw the implementation and management of email whitelisting systems, as well as creating return to office technology guides.

Mentored new employees across business as part of onboarding for tech requirements.

## PREVIOUS WORK EXPERIENCE

Service Desk Analyst| BUPA - Contract - Short term

Apr 2019 to Dec 2019

Service Delivery Analyst| World Wide Technology - Contract - Short term
Apr 2019 to Dec 2019

1st Line Support Analyst |Tata Consultancy Services - Contract - Short term Nov 2018 to Apr 2019

1st Line Support Analyst | Department for Education - Contract - Short term Aug 2018 to Nov 2018

IT Service Desk Analyst | HSS Hire - Contract - Short term

May 2018 to Aug 2018

1st Line Support Analyst | Interact Intranet - Contract - Short term Jul 2017 to Oct 2017

Personal Claims Manager | Think Money Group

Mar 2017 to Jul 2017

Media Sales Executive | Reed.co.uk

Apr 2016 to Mar 2017

Live Chat Advisor | The Chat Shop

Nov 2015 to Feb 2016

Health Care Associate | Vitality Health

Jan 2015 to Nov 2015

Continuous Improvement Project Assistant | Sky

Jun 2013 to Dec 2014

#### **EDUCATION**

BTEC - ICT - Pass grade Stockport College 2006-2008

8 GCSEs - Eng, Maths, Sci, French and ICT. St James RC High School 2000-2005

#### **HOBBIES**

Football Reading Music Writing Traveling Food Podcasts Futurology Tech Trends